Souradip Ghosh

Security Compliance Engineer

A solid foundation of application security-related experience combined with 5 years of experience in UI design and Frontend development in Web Applications (API Manager and Enterprise Repository) primarily on JQuery, JavaScript & Semantic UI. I aim to continue learning about what the field has to offer while specializing in specific areas, such as Application Security Testing and other Application Security-related fields.



- Bangalore, India
- in linkedin.com/in/souradip-ghosh

- +91-8951174685
- souradipghosh.in/
 - github.com/souro1212/JSON-XML-things

WORK EXPERIENCE

Security Compliance Engineer

Security & Compliance Team/ Torry Harris Integration Solutions Pvt. Ltd

02/2020 - Present

Bangalore

Achievements/Tasks

- Performed POC on Acunetix Web Application Security Scanner for scanning Torry Harris products and integrated with SDLC
- Performed POC on WhiteSource for scanning Torry Harris products and integrated with SDLC
- Performed VAPT and GDPR check on 5 products
- Found Billion laughs DOS attack on different THBS products and helped to mitigate it
- Found vertical privilege escalation leads to entire application takeover vulnerability in DMAPIM and fixed it

Frontend UI Developer

DM API Manager / Torry Harris Integration Solutions Pvt. Ltd

08/2016 - 02/2020

Banaalore

Achievements/Tasks

- Trained team members about OWASP Top 10 vulnerabilities and mitigation techniques
- Automated application security testing activities using Burp Suite Professional Edition
- Nominated to be the team representative for all GDPR compliance activities
- Trained other teams on application security testing and created an environment set-up manual using Burp Suite Community Edition
- Learned application security using Burp Suite in very short time
- Redesigned and implemented one of the portals of the application entirely responsive.
- Explored alternative UI and JS frameworks for responsiveness and pre-built templates as a part of the UI and UX revamp PoC
- Designed and implemented Content Security Policy (CSP) for the product including phased upgrade of jQuery and Semantic UI libraries

SKILLS

Web Application Penetration Testing CSS3 W3 CSS XALA Semantic UI

D3(Data-Driven Documents)

AWS (S3, Route 53, CM, Cloud Front)

TOOLS

Acunetix Web Application Security Scanner

OWASP ZAP WhiteSource

Kali Linux

Burp Suite Community and Professional Edition

NMAP & ZENMAP

MySQL Workbench

Eclips IDE

VS Code

PERSONAL PROJECTS

JSON-XML Things (05/2021 - Present)

- JSON-XML Things is a validator, reformatter and converter for JSON & XML, this javascript based application process all the data locally. Copy and paste or directly type and let JSON-XML Things tidy and validate your messy JSON/XML code.
- http://souradipghosh.in/JSON%20&%20XML%20formatter/
- https://github.com/souro1212/JSON-XML-things

LANGUAGES

Bengali English Hindi

INTERESTS

Aquarist

InfoSec Enthusiast

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend UI Developer

RepoPro 3.0 / Torry Harris Integration Solutions Pvt. Ltd

08/2016 - 01/2019

Bangalore

Achievements/Tasks

- Designed, developed and maintained almost 75% of the UI
- Designed and developed data visualization tree using D3 enabling a clear view of asset relationship and interdependencies, ease of navigation
- Improved applications performance by implementing different UI techniques
- Secured the entire application from XSS attacks
- Performed manual/automated Security Testing of the web application

EDUCATION

B.E. in Electrical and Electronics Engineering

Sir M. Visvesvaraya Institute of Technology, Bangalore

2012 - 2016

B.E. in Electrical and Electronics Engineering with an aggregate of

Achievements

- Ranked 7th in Shell Eco Marathon Asia 2015, Manila
- Quarterfinalist in Texas Instruments Innovation Challenge 2015, India

Higher Secondary Education

Birbhum Zilla School, West Bengal

2010 - 2012

Higher Secondary with an aggregate of 86%

Secondary Education

Birbhum Zilla School, West Bengal

2008 - 2010

Secondary with an aggregate of 90%